Ernesto Lopez

Contact: (856) 343-7875 | <u>titolopez44@yahoo.com</u>

Summary:

Aspiring web developer, fortunate to have received a crash course in business over ten years; with experience in warehouse operations, sales, customer service, catalog management systems, logistics, distribution, vendor relations, buying, inventory management, marketing efforts and ecommerce software. Grew with RevZilla.com from 10 employees to over 1,000. \$20M in revenue to over \$500M. Still along for the ride.

Traits: Inquisitive listener, ultimate solution seeker, sharp attention to detail

Skills: Excel user (functions, etc), Javascript, Html/CSS, Adobe Ps/Ai,

Employment:

RevZilla.com

Feb 2014 - Current, Buyer

- Curated brands and product selection
- Adapted low-tech, small vendors to our system and processes
- Adapted special order products to fit our customer service model
- Created and implemented Vendor Agreements
- Negotiated margins by leveraging high growth potential and value driven efforts
- Managed vendor relationships and expectations
- Created and managed purchase orders
- Coordinated marketing & on-site ad efforts
- Managed inventory levels

Sep 2011 - 2013, Logistics Associate

- Managed distribution queues of all customer and vendor orders
- Followed up on overdue customer drop ships with vendors
- Followed up on overdue stock orders
- Coordinated with customer service to manage customer expectations on fulfillment guarantees
- Implemented vendor on-boarding process

Sep 2011 - 2014, Catalog Associate

- Cataloged accessories and vehicle specific parts for sale on our site
- Managed and sold blemished/used inventory on company eBay account

Feb 2011 - 2018, Revzilla Store Associate (Part time)

- Sales and product expert on Saturday shifts and as backup on busy weekdays
 - Developed and inspired connections to our brand, offerings and sport to our clientele

Feb 2011 - Fulfillment, Receiving, Warehouse management

- Packed customer orders
- Received vendor shipments
- Organized an exponentially growing inventory

Education:

2010, Graduated from Timber Creek High School, Sicklerville, NJ